<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/team/</guid>
      <description>Co-Leads
Nathan Brunelle&amp;nbsp;
David EvansAssistantsComing soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning Survey</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/summersurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/summersurvey/</guid>
      <description>This email was sent out to students registered for the Fall 2020 course. If you are not registered yet but interested in taking the course in the fall, please read the message below and submit the survey. Thanks!
Mail Sent  Date: Wed, Jul 15, 2020 at 10:16 AM Subject: cs3102: Welcome and Survey Request
Dear Theory of Computation Students,
Thank you for registering for cs3102!
We’re looking forward to the fall semester, as much as one can under these circumstances, and considering plans for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2020 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall2020/</guid>
      <description>A version of this course will be offered in Fall 2020. It is optimistically scheduled for Mondays and Wednesdays, 3:30-4:45 in McLeod Hall 1020 (assuming we will be back to cramming 300 students in a classroom in the fall).
In the happy event that we can offer courses normally in the fall, the content and structure will be fairly similar to what was done in recent semesters. You can see all the materials from recent versions of this course here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources for cs3102.
Course Book Main Website
Full Text PDF
Github (if you have corrections or suggestions for the book, submit them to Boaz Barak here; useful contributions will be worth bonus points in the course, so let us know if you have a pull request accepted or start a useful issue)
Background Reading Mathematics for Computer Science (free PDF) by Eric Lehman, F Thomson Leighton, Albert R Meyer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Google Calendar for cs3102Upcoming Deadlines
The semester has concluded! There are no more deadlines for cs3102.
Classes
28 Aug: Class 1: Course Introduction (TCS Chapter 0)
2 Sept: Class 2: Defining Definitions (TCS Chapter 1)
4 Sept: Class 3: What Can Be Represented by Bits? (TCS Chapter 2)
9 Sept: Class 4: What Cannot Be Represented by Bits? (Uncountable Sets) 11 Sept: Class 5: Defining Computation (TCS Chapter 3)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS0</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/ps0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/ps0/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 0: Getting Started Hello students, Problem Set 0 is available here: ps0.pdf (you will also need the ps0.zip file described in the PDF). It is due on Friday, 6 September at 4:19pm.
The goal of this assignment is to get you acquainted with the tools we will be using for future assignments this semester: LaTeX (and overleaf) and Jupyter notebooks (using Python).
For this assignment you will be editing the ps0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Pledge</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</guid>
      <description>PDF for PrintingHonor Expectations As a student at the University of Virginia, you are trusted to be honorable and expected to behave in ways that merit that trust. We take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment for everyone. In particular, students in cs3102 are expected to follow these rules throughout the course:
I will not lie, cheat or steal. If I am unsure whether something would be considered lying, cheating or stealing, I will ask before doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>cs3102 Course Syllabus [PDF]
cs3102 Course Pledge [PDF]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>