<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>You will find Quiz 1 in GradeScope and should submit it by Wednesday at 9:59pm.
Problem Set 1 is due Monday, 30 Jan at 9:59pm.
Slides from class: class2.pdf (video is available for students in collab)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/ps1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/ps1/</guid>
      <description>Due: Monday, 30 January, 9:59pm This problem set includes problems that you will do on ``pencil-and-paper&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and writeup using the LaTeX template we provide, and problems that involve programming that you will do using a Jupyter notebook, a convenient way to edit and run Python code and integrate code with formatted text.
LaTeX Problems Problem Set 1 (you should find the link to the overleaf template in gradescope and follow the directions in the PDF to get started)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 1 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/problem-set-1-posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/problem-set-1-posted/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 1 is now posted and due on Monday, 30 January (9:59pm).
You should be able to access the problem set through gradescope, and you will need to submit your answers there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the material for the first class:
 Syllabus (which includes the Course Pledge Jeremy Kun, Habits of highly mathematical people (you should read this before submitting the course registration survey) Course Registration Survey (Due: Monday, 23 January, 8:59pm)  Slides from class: class1.pdf (video is available for students in collab)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Pledge</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</guid>
      <description>Honor Expectations As a student at the University of Virginia, you are trusted to be honorable and expected to behave in ways that merit that trust. We take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment for everyone. In particular, students in cs3120 are expected to follow these rules throughout the course:
I will not lie, cheat or steal. If I am unsure whether something would be considered lying, cheating or stealing, I will ask before doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Office Hours Mondays
9:30 - 10:30am (Dave, Rice 507)
1:00 - 3:00pm (Gillian, Rice 442)
1:30 - 3:00pm (Ratik, Rice 442)
3:30-5:30pm (Catherine, Rice 442)
Tuesdays
11:00am - noon (Dave, after class to Rice 507)
1:00 - 2:00pm (Mohammad, Rice 511)
3:00 - 5:00pm (Leah, Rice 442)
4:00 - 6:00pm (Zihan, Rice 442)
Wednesdays
12:30 - 2:30pm (Catherine, Rice 442)
2:00 - 3:00pm (Ratik, Rice 442)
3:00 - 5:00pm (Alex, Rice 442)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Theory of Computation</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Theory of Computation (renumbered as cs3120, but very similar to the course previously numbered as cs3102) will be offered in Spring 2023, co-taught by Mohammad Mahmoody and David Evans.
Class meetings will be Tuesdays and Thursdays, 9:30 – 10:45am in Olsson Hall 120.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be putting more information here about the course as the start of the semester approaches.
For now, you can see what the course was like in previous semesters from Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>This syllabus is not yet finalized, and is subject to change until distributed on the first day of class. The course website is managed through a public github repository, so you can see past versions there. The version as posted on the first day of class is here.
Overview Course Description: The goal of this course is to understand the fundamental limits on what can be efficiently computed in our universe and other possible (or imaginary) universes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources for cs3102. If you discover other resources you think would be helpful for students in the class, please let us know to add them here.
Course Book Main Website
Full Text PDF
Github (if you have corrections or suggestions for the book, submit them to Boaz Barak here; useful contributions will be worth bonus points in the course, so let us know if you have a pull request accepted or start a useful issue)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/python/</guid>
      <description>If you already have python3 on your machine, you should be good to go for the programming problems.
If you don’t, please follow these directions to download Python and PyCharm (you’re welcome to use any IDE that you want, we semi-arbitrarily picked PyCharm).
Windows   Install Python 3.6.4 (If you have a different version of Python, you still must install 3.6.4 seperately!):
  Download the executable x86-64 installer from python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>