<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning Survey</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/summersurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/summersurvey/</guid>
      <description>This email was sent out to students registered for the Fall 2020 course. If you are not registered yet but interested in taking the course in the fall, please read the message below and submit the survey. Thanks!
Mail Sent  Date: Wed, Jul 15, 2020 at 10:16 AM Subject: cs3102: Welcome and Survey Request
Dear Theory of Computation Students,
Thank you for registering for cs3102!
We’re looking forward to the fall semester, as much as one can under these circumstances, and considering plans for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2020 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/fall2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/fall2020/</guid>
      <description>A version of this course will be offered in Fall 2020. It is optimistically scheduled for Mondays and Wednesdays, 3:30-4:45 in McLeod Hall 1020 (assuming we will be back to cramming 300 students in a classroom in the fall).
In the happy event that we can offer courses normally in the fall, the content and structure will be fairly similar to what was done in Fall 2019, and you can see all the materials from that course on this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 3 Comments</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam3results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam3results/</guid>
      <description>Exam 3 and solutions to Exam 3 are posted here:
Exam 3
Exam 3 Comments
Oral Exam Requests. Out of 157 students who filled in something we could interpret as a grade for the Oral Exam Request on the last page, there were 40 who filled in the exact grade they received in the course, 109 who filled in a lower grade than they received (of whom 50 received at least a full letter grade higher than the minimum grade entered), and 8 who filled in a higher grade than the grade we determined was appropriate (and have the opportunity to improve their grade by doing an oral exam).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 24: Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class24/</guid>
      <description>Exam 3 will be in class on Wednesday.
Slides
Video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 23: More NP Completeness</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class23/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 14: NP, NP completeness, and the Cook-Levin Theorem</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Exam 3</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam3/</guid>
      <description>Exam 3 will be Wednesday, 4 December at the normal class time in the normal classroom. We will aim to start the exam right at 3:30pm, so you will benefit from arriving early for class Wednesday to be settled and ready to start the exam. This is the final exam for the class and we will not use the registrar-scheduled final exam time, but recall from the course syllabus that there will still be an opportunity for students who feel they were &amp;ldquo;not be able to demonstrate their best ability during a 75 minute in-class exam, &amp;hellip; to request an oral final exam to be scheduled with one of the instructors during the exam period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 22: NP Completeness</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class22/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 14: NP, NP completeness, and the Cook-Levin Theorem
Cook&amp;rsquo;s Paper
Levin&amp;rsquo;s Paper (Translated)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 21: Is Omniscience Helpful?</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class21/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 14: NP, NP completeness, and the Cook-Levin Theorem
The Longest Path (Lyrics by Daniel Barrett)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 7</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps7/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 7: Is P a proper subset of NP? Problem Set 7 is available here: ps7.pdf (you will also need the ps7.zip file). It is due on Tuesday, 26 November at 7:29pm.
Note that PS7 is considerably longer than previous problem sets, and you have a longer time period to complete it. I covers a lot of challenging material from recent (and upcoming) classes and book chapters 11-14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 20: Polynomial-Time Reductions</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class20/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 11: Efficient computation
TCS Chapter 12: Modeling running time
TCS Chapter 13: Polynomial-time reductions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 19: Turing maching running time</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class19/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 11: Efficient computation
TCS Chapter 12: Modeling running time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 2 Results</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2results/</guid>
      <description>The comments on Exam 2 are here: Exam 2 Comments
The exam is: Exam 2
Overall, this exam was more difficult than Exam 1 and several of the problems turned out to be quite challenging (actually, three of them were impossible!).
The average scores by problem (as explained on the cover sheet, the score for a good answer for each problem was 9, other than the Cover where a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; answer was worth 6 points) are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 18: Review for Exam 2</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class18/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
Exam 2 Practice Problems
Exam 2 Preparation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Problems for Exam 2</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2practice/</guid>
      <description>By popular request, here are some practice problems for preparing to Exam 2: [PDF]
We won&amp;rsquo;t be providing written solutions to these problems, but are happy to answer questions about them (including during office hours). If you would like any particular problems to be included in the review class (Monday), let us know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS4 Grades Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps4grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps4grades/</guid>
      <description>The grades for PS4 are now posted in Assignments on Collab. You will find your grades, comments, and an attached pdf of solutions with PS2 assignment
Our grading policy for PS4 was the same as for PS1, PS2, and PS3, but we reserve the right to change this policy for future assignments.
To calculate your grade we first computed the following:
 five_count = the count of problems for which you earned a 5 or above sum = the sum of the scores earned on all problems non_star_count = the number of non-starred problems in the assignent score_by_fives = five_count / non_star_count score_by_average = sum / non_star_count  That policy was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Exam 2</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam2/</guid>
      <description>Exam 2 will be Wednesday, 6 November at the normal class time in the normal classroom. We will aim to start the exam right at 3:30pm, so you will benefit from arriving early for class Wednesday to be settled and ready to start the exam.
Exam 2 will cover material from Classes 1-16 (through 28 October) (so the new material introduced on Rice&amp;rsquo;s Theorem in Class 17 is not covered in this exam), Problem Sets 1-6 (comments for PS4 and PS5 are now available in collab, sorry it has taken so long to get the grading done for these, but you can see our solutions and comments in collab now; we will post comments for Problem Set 6 on Sunday afternoon), and the textbook chapters 0-6 and parts of 8 (8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 17: Rice&#39;s Theorem</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class17/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 8: Universaility and Uncomputability</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 16: Reductions</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class16/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 8: Universaility and Uncomputability</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 6</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps6/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 6: Dodge Duck Dip Dive Decide Problem Set 6 is available here: ps6.pdf (you will also need the ps6.zip file). It is due on Friday, 1 November at 4:19pm.
These is no Jupyter part for PS6, so your submission can be just one ps6.pdf file.
This assignment covers Turing Machines from Chapter 6, and undecidability (including the halting problem, reductions, and Rice&amp;rsquo;s theorem) from Chapter 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 15: Universality and Uncomputability</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class15/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 8: Universaility and Uncomputability
Alan M. Turing, On Computable Numbers, with an Application to the Entscheidungsproblem. 1936. (bug fix) (You missed your chance to by an original printing for GBP 30,000.)
According to Scott Aaronson, Dori-Mic and the Universal Machine! A Tragicomic Tale of Combinatorics and Computability for Curious Children of All Ages is &amp;ldquo;The BEST babies&amp;rsquo; book about computational universality I&amp;rsquo;ve read.&amp;quot;. I have free copies available for anyone who needs a holiday present for a young sibling/cousin/nibling/other person who is behind in her theoretical computer science education and needs a holiday present for any cs3102 students who ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 5 Update</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5update2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5update2/</guid>
      <description>Two more updates to PS5:
  Problem 7 considered adding an array but not loops to NAND-CIRC. But, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to have arrays without any way to update the index used to access them. So, for this to make sense we need to also have an instruction to update i. So, we have modified this question to add conditional increment and decrement instructions:
  CINC v takes a regular variable as its input, and if the value of v is 1 it updates the value of i to be i + 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 5 Update</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5update/</guid>
      <description>There were several mistakes in PS5, Problem 1, which are now corrected (updated ps5.pdf, ps5.zip).
Problem 1a should be:
 Prove that when $f^*(i) = 0$, $f_{i+1} = f_i$. That is, the two functions denoted by $f_{i + 1}$ and $f_i$ are actually the same function.  Thanks to Joey Rudek for noticing the problem!
Problems 6 and 7 mixed up NAND-CIRC and NAND-TM. Problem 6 should be asking if NAND-LOOP is more powerful than NAND-CIRC (it would be silly to ask if it is more powerful than NAND-TM, since NAND-TM has everything in NAND-LOOP plus arrays, so there&amp;rsquo;s no way NAND-LOOP could be more powerful than NAND-TM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 14: Computability</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class14/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 6: Loops and Infinity
TCS Chapter 8: Universaility and Uncomputability
Alan M. Turing, On Computable Numbers, with an Application to the Entscheidungsproblem. 1936. (bug fix)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 5</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps5/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 5: Loopy Tunes Problem Set 5 is available here: ps5.pdf (you will also need the ps5.zip file). It is due on Friday, 25 October at 4:19pm.
These is no Jupyter part for PS5, so your submission can be just one ps5.pdf file.
This assignment covers the Size Hierarchy from Chapter 5, Finite State Macines from Class 12 and Class 13, and Turing Machines, NAND-TM, and computability from Chapter 5, Class 13 and Class 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 13: Machines</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class13/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 6: Loops and Infinity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 12: Size Hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class12/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 5: Code as data, data as code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 4</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps4/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 4: Countess of Functions Problem Set 4 is available here: ps4.pdf (you will also need the ps4.zip file). It is due on Friday, 18 October at 4:19pm.
This assignment involves both PDF and Jupyter parts, and you should submit both your ps4.ipynb and ps4.pdf files as attachments in collab. As far as we know, none of the problems are impossible (we may be wrong, of course, but none of them are intentionally impossible to solve).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 11: Cost and Counting</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class11/</guid>
      <description>Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 5: Code as data, data as code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 1 Comments</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam1comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam1comments/</guid>
      <description>The comments on Exam 1 are here: PDF.
The original exam is here: PDF
Overall the class did very well on Exam 1. The average scores by problem are:
  Cover123456789   159.89.39.89.56.78.78.88.97.9   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Break</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/fallbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/fallbreak/</guid>
      <description>Enjoy your Fall Break!
We will have no regularly scheduled office hours until after classes resume on October 9. We will return Exam 1 in class on Wednesday, October 9. There is no problem set due next week. Problem Set 4 will be due on Friday, 18 October.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 10: Exam Review</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class10/</guid>
      <description>Exam 1 is in class Wednesday.
Please read the cover sheet before the exam: Exam 1 Cover Sheet
Problem Set 3 Comments (PDF in collab).
Practice Problems Comments
Slides
Video
Quantum supremacy using a programmable superconducting processor, Google AI Quantum and collaborators. Leaked preprint, August 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 9: Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class9/</guid>
      <description>Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 3 is due this Monday (2:59pm). Note the schedule change resulting from the interaction between fall break and the exam, which will be in class, Wednesday, 2 October.
Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 5: Code as data, data as code
The book assumes readers are already familiar with asymptotic operators, so doesn&amp;rsquo;t include a lot of explanation on this or exercises. You probably have also encountered these in other classes, but without a formal definition of their meaning (and possibly misused in confusing ways).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS2 Grades Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps2grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps2grades/</guid>
      <description>The grades for PS2 are now posted in Assignments on Collab. You will find your grades, comments, and an attached pdf of solutions with PS2 assignment
Our grading policy for PS2 was the same as for PS1, but we reserve the right to change this policy for future assignments. That policy was:
 You earned an A if you got at least 80% 5&amp;rsquo;s or an average of at least 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 8: Complexity</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class8/</guid>
      <description>Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 3 is due this Monday (2:59pm). Note the schedule change resulting from the interaction between fall break and the exam, which will be in class, Wednesday, 2 October.
Slides
Video
TCS Chapter 4: syntactic sugar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Exam 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/exam1/</guid>
      <description>Exam 1 will be next Wednesday, 2 October at the normal class time in the normal classroom. We will aim to start the exam right at 3:30pm, so you will benefit from arriving early for class Wednesday to be settled and ready to start the exam.
Exam 1 will cover material from Classes 1-9 8 (through 25 23 September) [Note: we have revised the coverage scope to not include any new material from Class 9 on Exam 1], Problem Sets 1-3 (including the comments we provide on them; we will post comments for Problem Set 3 shortly after it is due on September 30), and the textbook chapters 0-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 3 Update</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps3update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps3update/</guid>
      <description>There are a few important updates to Problem Set 3.
  As originally stated, we believe Problem J2 is impossible. We have modified the problem to add the constant function ZERO to the gate set (which you can represent using 0 in Python. We believe it is impossible to solve without this. We have added an optional (double starred!) problem 5 to the PDF part of the assignment which asks you to prove that the question as originally asked (and in Exercise 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS1 Grades Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps1grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps1grades/</guid>
      <description>The grades for PS1 are now posted. We&amp;rsquo;re really sorry this took so long! Hopefully we have a process in place now that will be much faster and more reliable at grading and returning homeworks.
Please look at the posted comments on PS1 in collab: [PDF] (only accessible to students in the class)
When assigning grades we sought to reward individual solutions that were high quality and total submissions that were overall decent, while not harshly punishing mild mistakes or narrow misconceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 3</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps3/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 3: Sugary Finite Computation Problem Set 3 is available here: ps3.pdf (you will also need the ps3.zip file described in the PDF). It is due on Monday, 30 September at 2:59pm. (Note the unusual due date and time. The schedule is unusual because of Exam 1, which will be held Wednesday, 2 October, in class.)
The purpose of this assignment is to continue to develop your understanding of finite computation, focusing on the material in Chapter 4 of the textbook and what we cover in Class 7 and Class 8 and Class 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 7: Syntactic Sugar</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class7/</guid>
      <description>Class 7: Syntactic Sugar Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 2 is due this Friday (4:19pm).
Slides
Video of slides
Video of Nate&amp;rsquo;s Laptop
TCS Chapter 4: syntactic sugar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 6: Defining Boolean Circuits</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class6/</guid>
      <description>Class 6: Defining Boolean Circuits Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 2 is due this Friday (4:19pm).
Slides (PDF)
Video
TCS Chapter 3: Defining computation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS2 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 2: Fine Finite Computation Problem Set 2 is available here: ps2.pdf (you will also need the ps2.zip file described in the PDF). It is due on Friday, 20 September at 4:19pm.
In this assignment we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with models of finite computation.
This assignment involves only pencil-and-paper problems (submitted as a PDF by editing the provided ps2.tex template) and there is no programming portion.
Submit your completed ps2.pdf as an attachment via collab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 5: Defining Computation</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class5/</guid>
      <description>Class 5: Defining Computation Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 1 is due this Friday (4:19pm).
See the schedule for updated office hours.
Slides (PDF)
Video
TCS Chapter 3: Defining computation
Daniel Lewin, 14 May 1970 – 11 September 2001 Hiawatha Bray. A Lost Spirit Still Inspires, Boston Globe, 4 September 2011.
Tom Leighton&amp;rsquo;s Remarks on Danny Lewin
No Better Time: The Brief, Remarkable Life of Danny Lewin, the Genius Who Transformed the Internet by Molly Knight Raskin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 4: Uncountability</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class4/</guid>
      <description>What Cannot Be Represented by Bits? (Uncountable Sets) Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 1 is due this Friday (4:19pm). See the schedule for updated office hours.
Slides (PDF)
Video
Here is Cantor&amp;rsquo;s original proof (in German, but the math is universal, so somewhat understandable even without knowing German):
Georg Cantor, Ueber eine elementare Frage der Mannigfaltigkeitslehre. Published in Jahresbericht der Deutschen Mathematiker-Vereinigung, Volume 1, 1891. (About this Scan)
Its only a bit over 2 pages long, and its easy to see Cantor&amp;rsquo;s answer to the ``Is 0 a Natural Number?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS1 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps1/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 1: (Un)natural Numbers Problem Set 1 is available here: ps1.pdf (you will also need the ps1.zip file described in the PDF). It is due on Friday, 13 September at 4:19pm.
In this assignment we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with constructive recursive definitions (mostly the definition of natural numbers discussed in lecture), and proofs by induction.
Similarly to Problem Set 0, this assigned involves both pencil-and-paper problems (submitted as a PDF by editing the provided ps1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 3: Countable Sets</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class3/</guid>
      <description>What Can Be Represented by Bits? Schedule Reminders: Problem Set 0 is due this Friday (4:19pm). See the schedule for updated office hours.
Slides (PDF)
Video
Update (7 Sept): There is a correction on slide 10 to the way we defined addition for the Set-based Natural Numbers (thanks to Nijat Khanbabayev for pointing out the problem).
Some of the material from today&amp;rsquo;s class (and what we will continue on Monday) is in the TCS Book, Chapter 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2: Defining Definitions</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/class2/</guid>
      <description>Schedule Reminders: Office hours start today! Full schedule (which will be updated) is posted here. The first office hours are tonight, 6:30-8pm, in Rice 442.
Is 0 a Natural Number?
Slides (PDF)
Video
The &amp;ldquo;Google dragon&amp;rdquo; image was drawn for this talk. You can find Sergey Brin&amp;rsquo;s resume here (note the high honors in Mathematics and (low) honors in Computer Science).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/office-hours-posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/office-hours-posted/</guid>
      <description>Office hours have now been posted on the Course Schedule. These will be adjusted and likely some more office hours added over the next few weeks, but we wanted to have some posted now for help on Problem Set 0 as well the background material we are covering this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Pledge</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/pledgeposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/pledgeposted/</guid>
      <description>To be in this class, students are expected to agree to the Course Pledge. The expectations there apply to everything connected with this class including all assignments, classes, and office hours.
Before 2:59pm this Wednesday (Sept 4) you must read and agree to the contents of the Course Pledge, and submit this assignment (in collab) to acknowledge having done this. (It is not necessary to print and submit the pledge on paper or as a scanned PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS0 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps0posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/ps0posted/</guid>
      <description>Problem Set 0: Getting Started Hello students, Problem Set 0 is available here: ps0.pdf (you will also need the ps0.zip file described in the PDF). It is due on Friday, 6 September at 4:19pm.
The goal of this assignment is to get you acquainted with the tools we will be using for future assignments this semester: LaTeX (and overleaf) and Jupyter notebooks (using Python).
For this assignment you will be editing the ps0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/lecture1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/lecture1/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 1: Course Introduction Today we will be discussing course mechanics, course expectations, and the values of studying theory.
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Registration Survey</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/survey/</guid>
      <description>Please complete the course registration survey by 4:19pm on Friday, August 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>The course syllabus and pledge are now posted:
Syllabus (PDF)
Pledge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/f19/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the website for cs3102: Theory of Computation! More information will be posted here soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>