<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 10 is now posted - see the Week 10 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wherefore Turing Machines?</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/wherefore-turing-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/wherefore-turing-machines/</guid>
      <description>The slides for class from Wednesday, 27 October are here: oct27.pdf
Turing&amp;rsquo;s paper is: A. M. Turing, On Computable Numbers, with an Application to the Entscheidungsproblem, 12 November 1936.
Charles Petzold&amp;rsquo;s book, The Annotated Turing: A Guided Tour Through Alan Turing&amp;rsquo;s Historic Paper on Computability and the Turing Machine provides a detailed explanation of everything in the paper and is a great read.
John Graham-Comming&amp;rsquo;s blog post that led to the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s apology is here: Alan Turing deserves an apology from the British Government (23 June, 2009).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class: Cost of NFAs</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class-cost-of-nfas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class-cost-of-nfas/</guid>
      <description>The slides for class from Wednesday, 20 October are here: oct20.pdf
There are lots more complexities in implementing DFAs efficiently on GPUs. This paper explains some of them: Why GPUs are Slow at Executing NFAs and How to Make them Faster, Hongyuan Liu, Sreepathi Pai, Adwiat Jog. In ASPLOS 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 9 is now posted - see the Week 9 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Solutions</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm-solutions/</guid>
      <description>We have posted solutions and discussion for the Self-Assessment Midterm here: midterm_solutions.pdf
The slides for the class discussion on the midterm are here: PDF. The class is also recorded, which you can find in collab: Course Recordings
We encourage all students to read through the solutions and revisit your own answers to identify gaps in your understanding. We will definitely have several questions on the Final Exam intended to test your understanding of the same topics as on the midterm, and those questions will be similar to the ones here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 8 is now posted - see the Week 8 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assessment Midterm</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm/</guid>
      <description>The Self-Assessment Midterm is posted here: midterm.pdf
This self-assessment midterm is intended to help prepare you to do well on the final by giving you experience taking an exam, but without any grade pressure or logistical challenges.
This exam will not be graded, but you do need to upload an image of your exam by 2:59pm Wednesday, 13 October. You are encouraged to print out the exam to do on paper, and take it under realistic exam conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Poincare on Scientists in Politics</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/poincare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/poincare/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Calvin Kuo for finding the original source of the Poincaré quote.
La Revue politique et littéraire (page 708), 1904. PDF
Below is a translation, done mostly by Google translate, but with corrections by Anh Nguyen Tuong.
Mr. Henry Poincare, from the Academy of Sciences, member of the Bureau des Longitudes, professor at the Sorbonne, chief mining engineer, author of nearly three hundred original papers which have renowned by their contribution of discoveries and insights, the mathematical physics and celestial mechanics, emits on the political activity of scientists this opinion of good sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sep 29 Class Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/sep29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/sep29/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Wednesday, 29 September&amp;rsquo;s class are here: sep29.pdf.
The full fabricated interview with Henri Poincaré is Mathematics is the art of giving the same name to different things by Ferdinand Verhulst, 3 September 2012.
The quote I used on the last slide is (translated) from La Revue Bleue (Revue politique et littéraire) 1904:
 Well, this time I have to excuse myself; everybody will have to choose according to his conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 6 is now posted - see the Week 6 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 5 is now posted - see the Week 5 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/survey-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/survey-results/</guid>
      <description>The slides summarizing the survey results that I discussed in Monday&amp;rsquo;s class are here: surveyresults.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 6 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class6/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 6 (Wednesday, 15 September) are here: class6.pdf
One important correction from the class: I was spectacularly wrong about Jay-Z not being &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo;. I was just thinking about his music income, and even spectacularly successful musicians usually capture such a small fraction of the value that they create that very few are &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo;. For purposes of this discussion, I&amp;rsquo;ll define &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo; as having net worth over $1B, and &amp;ldquo;really rich&amp;rdquo; as having net worth over $100M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 4 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class4/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 4 (Wednesday, 8 September) are here: class4.pdf
Here&amp;rsquo;s the video on &amp;ldquo;Music and Measure Theory&amp;rdquo;:
   Thanks to the student who pointed out that the most likely explanation of why the most widely used music tone system has twelve tones is due to the property you get by going up by fifths (multiplying frequency by 3/2).
Music theorists call this the &amp;ldquo;Circle of Fifths&amp;rdquo; (and will draw it as a circle, returning to the tone after 12 hops), and there are some good explanations why the 12-tone arrangement has mathematical advantages (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 4 is now posted - see the Week 4 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 3 is now posted - see the Week 3 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 2 (1 September) are here: class2.pdf
Some relevant links for the class:
  Companies by Market Capitalization (Facebook is now down to $1.060, from $1.069 on Wednesday morning, so there is still hope they will fall off the list.)
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the one paper from a Google co-founder that I could find which actuall contains a legitimate theorem and proof: Sergey Brin, Rajeev Motwani, Craig Silverstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Update</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/course-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/course-update/</guid>
      <description>Our plan for how to use the full class meeting times has adapted from our original plan - we&amp;rsquo;ll provide more justification for the change below, but the plan now is:
  Monday classes will be for covering examples, providing context, and answering student questions about the current week&amp;rsquo;s content, designed to help students understand the materials you will be assessed on during your cohort meetings. These will be before any of that week&amp;rsquo;s assessed cohort meetings, so all students will have the chance to benefit from these before your assessed cohort meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehoursposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehoursposted/</guid>
      <description>Hello, The office hours schedule has now been posted. You can find information on office hours (logistics, time, location) here: Office Hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 1 is now posted - see the Week 1 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 2 is now posted - see the Week 2 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Semester</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</guid>
      <description>First Class Meeting Our first scheduled class is Wednesday, 25 August, 3:30-4:45pm in Maury Hall 209 (weather permitting, we will also use the Ampitheater space outside Maury).
For this optional first class meeting, we will have an open &amp;ldquo;meet and greet&amp;rdquo; with an opportunity to ask any questions you would like of the course instructors, and an opportunity for students who wish to form their own cohorts (details below) to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2021 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</guid>
      <description>[Updated 18 August 2021]
The cs3102 course will be offered in Fall 2021, co-taught by Nathan Brunelle and David Evans.
Class meetings will be Mondays and Wednesday, 3:30pm - 4:45pm in Maury Hall 209. We will be sending out an email next week with details on the in-person class meetings, but they are being planned in a way that prioritizes safety and comfort while offering an in-person class experience.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be putting more information here about the course as the start of the semester approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
