<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 9 is now posted - see the Week 9 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 8 is now posted - see the Week 8 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week7posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week7posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 7 is now posted - see the Week 7 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cameras and Community</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/cameras-and-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/cameras-and-community/</guid>
      <description>In general, we&amp;rsquo;re pleased with the responses on the peer evaluation surveys, and it is clear that most students have respect for and are valuing the interactions with their cohortmates. But, one thing we&amp;rsquo;ve heard from some of your peer evaluation surveys, and also felt ourselves, is the difficulty forming a connected community in this on-line environment.
Groups that knew each other and were used to working together pre-pandemic usually were able to move to on-line environments fairly well, and the personal connections already established in the easier in-person environment translate to the on-line environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted Brunelle OH</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/brunelleoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/brunelleoh/</guid>
      <description>Professor Brunelle&amp;rsquo;s Office hours must be adjusted slightly. These Changes will begin for this week.
I (Nate) will still have office hours on Wednesdays at 12:00pm-2:00pm, but my Thursday office hours from 3:30pm-5pm will instead be held on Fridays 1:00pm-2:30pm.
The will be held in my zoom room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aPiazza</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/apiazza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/apiazza/</guid>
      <description>Since a few students asked about using Piazza, I wanted to post an explanation of why I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to use Piazza for any official course interactions here (these are my personal views, which don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reflect those of anyone else on the course staff).
The reason I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to use Piazza is their business model is based on surveillance of students and monetizing the data collected through this is ways that may be harmful to students forced to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 6 is now posted - see the Week 6 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 5 is now posted - see the Week 5 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/evals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/evals/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve had an opportunity to get to know our cohorts, we&amp;rsquo;d like to provide a way for you to offer feedback on how your cohort could work more effectively.
We have created a peer evaluation form for you to reflect on the ways that you and your cohort-mates contribute to your team dynamic. We ask that you please complete this feedback form by 11:59pm on Wednesdsay Sept 23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4, Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 is now posted - see the Week 4 page for the details.
The Resources page has some links to resources that we think will be useful for cs3102 students, including additional background materials, and other sources that cover concepts in the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting Assignments</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/submission/</guid>
      <description>To submit your write-ups and see your feedback, use this site: Assignment Submissions. This video explains how to use it: zoomcast
In general, you will only need to submit your weekly written problem, and only one member of your cohort needs to submit. Make sure you tell your cohort coach (TA) who is submitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Student Hours</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/openhours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/openhours/</guid>
      <description>Below is the schedule for open student hours (no one is in an office these days, but these are similar to what is sometimes called &amp;ldquo;office hours&amp;rdquo;).
These are times when there will be a course staff person available to answer any questions you have.
 	Monday	4-5:30pm		Nick	 	Monday	5:30-6pm		Yu	 	Monday	6:30-8pm		Anlan	 	Monday	8-9:30pm		Megan	 &amp;nbsp;		Tuesday	12:30-2pm		Timothy	 	Tuesday	2-3:30pm		Nijat	 	Tuesday	3:30-5pm		Jonah	 	Tuesday	5-6:30pm		Nick	 	Tuesday	6-7:30pm		Kush	 &amp;nbsp;		Wednesday	9:30-10:30am		Dave	 	Wednesday	noon-2:00pm		Nathan	 	Wednesday	noon-1:30pm		Timothy	 	Wednesday	1:30-3pm		Vi	 	Wednesday	7:30-9pm		Noah	    	Thursday	9:30-11am		John	 	Thursday	12:30-2pm		Joey	 	Thursday	2:30-4pm		Joshua	 	Thursday	4:30-6pm		Brandon	 	Thursday	6:30-8pm		Preston	 		Friday	9-10:30am		Yu	 	Friday	10:30-noon		Megan	 	Friday	12-1pm		Dave	 	Friday	1pm-2:30pm		Nathan	 	Friday	2-3:30pm		William	 	Friday	5:30-7:00pm		Nijat	 		Saturday	10-11:30am		Nicholas	 	Saturday	11:30am-1pm		Rachel	 		Sunday	10:30am-noon		Michelle	 	Sunday	3:30-5pm		Joshua	 	Sunday	5:30-7pm		Nicholas	    During the scheduled times, the listed staff person is available to answer your questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Class</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/firstmeeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/firstmeeting/</guid>
      <description>Our first (and only) full-class meeting will be held at 3:30pm Aug 26.
Join the meeting here: Zoom Session
We&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting these slides: Slides
We&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing course logistics, and the importance of studying theory.
We look forward to seeing you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/firstoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/firstoh/</guid>
      <description>We will post a more complete office hours schedule by early next week.
I (Dave) will have office hours on Wednesdays at 9:30-10:30am (including tomorrow, Wednesday, August 26) and Fridays at 10-11am (now: Fridays noon-1pm) (including this Friday, August 28). For now, these will use my zoom office (but these will move to the course discord server once everyone is set up there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Semester</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</guid>
      <description>First Class Meeting We will have our first meeting on Wednesday at our scheduled 3:30-4:45pm meeting time via zoom: zoom link.
Assessed cohort meetings will start (at the ealiest) on Tuesday, 1 September, so students scheduled in Tuesday cohorts will have preparation Cohort Meetings on Sunday (30 August), and will need to be ready with the Week 1 problems by their cohort meeting on 1 September. (Other students will have more time, depending on when your assessed cohort meeting is scheduled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning Survey</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/summersurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/summersurvey/</guid>
      <description>This email was sent out to students registered for the Fall 2020 course. If you are not registered yet but interested in taking the course in the fall, please read the message below and submit the survey. Thanks!
Mail Sent  Date: Wed, Jul 15, 2020 at 10:16 AM Subject: cs3102: Welcome and Survey Request
Dear Theory of Computation Students,
Thank you for registering for cs3102!
We’re looking forward to the fall semester, as much as one can under these circumstances, and considering plans for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2020 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall2020/</guid>
      <description>A version of this course will be offered in Fall 2020. It is optimistically scheduled for Mondays and Wednesdays, 3:30-4:45 in McLeod Hall 1020 (assuming we will be back to cramming 300 students in a classroom in the fall).
In the happy event that we can offer courses normally in the fall, the content and structure will be fairly similar to what was done in recent semesters. You can see all the materials from recent versions of this course here:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>