<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week11posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week11posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 11 is now posted - see the Week 11 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 10 is now posted - see the Week 10 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wherefore Turing Machines?</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/wherefore-turing-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/wherefore-turing-machines/</guid>
      <description>The slides for class from Wednesday, 27 October are here: oct27.pdf
Turing&amp;rsquo;s paper is: A. M. Turing, On Computable Numbers, with an Application to the Entscheidungsproblem, 12 November 1936.
Charles Petzold&amp;rsquo;s book, The Annotated Turing: A Guided Tour Through Alan Turing&amp;rsquo;s Historic Paper on Computability and the Turing Machine provides a detailed explanation of everything in the paper and is a great read.
John Graham-Comming&amp;rsquo;s blog post that led to the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s apology is here: Alan Turing deserves an apology from the British Government (23 June, 2009).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class: Cost of NFAs</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class-cost-of-nfas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class-cost-of-nfas/</guid>
      <description>The slides for class from Wednesday, 20 October are here: oct20.pdf
There are lots more complexities in implementing DFAs efficiently on GPUs. This paper explains some of them: Why GPUs are Slow at Executing NFAs and How to Make them Faster, Hongyuan Liu, Sreepathi Pai, Adwiat Jog. In ASPLOS 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 9 is now posted - see the Week 9 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Solutions</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm-solutions/</guid>
      <description>We have posted solutions and discussion for the Self-Assessment Midterm here: midterm_solutions.pdf
The slides for the class discussion on the midterm are here: PDF. The class is also recorded, which you can find in collab: Course Recordings
We encourage all students to read through the solutions and revisit your own answers to identify gaps in your understanding. We will definitely have several questions on the Final Exam intended to test your understanding of the same topics as on the midterm, and those questions will be similar to the ones here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 8 is now posted - see the Week 8 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assessment Midterm</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/midterm/</guid>
      <description>The Self-Assessment Midterm is posted here: midterm.pdf
This self-assessment midterm is intended to help prepare you to do well on the final by giving you experience taking an exam, but without any grade pressure or logistical challenges.
This exam will not be graded, but you do need to upload an image of your exam by 2:59pm Wednesday, 13 October. You are encouraged to print out the exam to do on paper, and take it under realistic exam conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Poincare on Scientists in Politics</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/poincare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/poincare/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Calvin Kuo for finding the original source of the Poincaré quote.
La Revue politique et littéraire (page 708), 1904. PDF
Below is a translation, done mostly by Google translate, but with corrections by Anh Nguyen Tuong.
_Mr. Henry Poincare, from the Academy of Sciences, member of the Bureau des Longitudes, professor at the Sorbonne, chief mining engineer, author of nearly three hundred original papers which have renowned by their contribution of discoveries and insights, the mathematical physics and celestial mechanics, emits on the political activity of scientists this opinion of good sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sep 29 Class Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/sep29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/sep29/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Wednesday, 29 September&amp;rsquo;s class are here: sep29.pdf.
The full fabricated interview with Henri Poincaré is Mathematics is the art of giving the same name to different things by Ferdinand Verhulst, 3 September 2012.
The quote I used on the last slide is (translated) from La Revue Bleue (Revue politique et littéraire) 1904:
 Well, this time I have to excuse myself; everybody will have to choose according to his conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 6 is now posted - see the Week 6 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 5 is now posted - see the Week 5 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/survey-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/survey-results/</guid>
      <description>The slides summarizing the survey results that I discussed in Monday&amp;rsquo;s class are here: surveyresults.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 6 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class6/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 6 (Wednesday, 15 September) are here: class6.pdf
One important correction from the class: I was spectacularly wrong about Jay-Z not being &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo;. I was just thinking about his music income, and even spectacularly successful musicians usually capture such a small fraction of the value that they create that very few are &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo;. For purposes of this discussion, I&amp;rsquo;ll define &amp;ldquo;really really rich&amp;rdquo; as having net worth over $1B, and &amp;ldquo;really rich&amp;rdquo; as having net worth over $100M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 4 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class4/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 4 (Wednesday, 8 September) are here: class4.pdf
Here&amp;rsquo;s the video on &amp;ldquo;Music and Measure Theory&amp;rdquo;:   
Thanks to the student who pointed out that the most likely explanation of why the most widely used music tone system has twelve tones is due to the property you get by going up by fifths (multiplying frequency by 3/2).
Music theorists call this the &amp;ldquo;Circle of Fifths&amp;rdquo; (and will draw it as a circle, returning to the tone after 12 hops), and there are some good explanations why the 12-tone arrangement has mathematical advantages (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 4 is now posted - see the Week 4 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 3 is now posted - see the Week 3 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>The slides for Class 2 (1 September) are here: class2.pdf
Some relevant links for the class:
 Companies by Market Capitalization (Facebook is now down to $1.060, from $1.069 on Wednesday morning, so there is still hope they will fall off the list.)
 Here&amp;rsquo;s the one paper from a Google co-founder that I could find which actuall contains a legitimate theorem and proof: Sergey Brin, Rajeev Motwani, Craig Silverstein. Beyond Market Baskets: Generalizing Association Rules to Correlations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Update</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/course-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/course-update/</guid>
      <description>Our plan for how to use the full class meeting times has adapted from our original plan - we&amp;rsquo;ll provide more justification for the change below, but the plan now is:
 Monday classes will be for covering examples, providing context, and answering student questions about the current week&amp;rsquo;s content, designed to help students understand the materials you will be assessed on during your cohort meetings. These will be before any of that week&amp;rsquo;s assessed cohort meetings, so all students will have the chance to benefit from these before your assessed cohort meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehours/</guid>
      <description>You can find instructor and TA office hours in the calendar below. Some office hours are held remotely, others in person, some both simultaneously. Make sure you check the location in the calendar.
Regardless of where the office hours are held, #help-requests channel in discord will be used as our office hours queue. To add yourself to the queue, simply post what you&amp;rsquo;re asking about (e.g. &amp;ldquo;week1 pancakes video&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;week 1 problem 5&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;countability&amp;rdquo;) and where you&amp;rsquo;re joining from (online versus in-person if there are multiple options at the same time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehoursposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/officehoursposted/</guid>
      <description>Hello, The office hours schedule has now been posted. You can find information on office hours (logistics, time, location) here: Office Hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 1 is now posted - see the Week 1 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 Posted</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2posted/</guid>
      <description>The guide and materials for Week 2 is now posted - see the Week 2 page for the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Pledge</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</guid>
      <description>Honor Expectations As a student at the University of Virginia, you are trusted to be honorable and expected to behave in ways that merit that trust. We take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment for everyone. In particular, students in cs3102 are expected to follow these rules throughout the course:
I will not lie, cheat or steal. If I am unsure whether something would be considered lying, cheating or stealing, I will ask before doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Semester</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</guid>
      <description>First Class Meeting Our first scheduled class is Wednesday, 25 August, 3:30-4:45pm in Maury Hall 209 (weather permitting, we will also use the Ampitheater space outside Maury).
For this optional first class meeting, we will have an open &amp;ldquo;meet and greet&amp;rdquo; with an opportunity to ask any questions you would like of the course instructors, and an opportunity for students who wish to form their own cohorts (details below) to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>For the open help schedule, see Open Student Hours.
For the detailed weekly schedule for each cohort, see one of the week postings (e.g., Week 1). 
  Introduction   
 Week 1: Mathematical Definitions    Wed 25 August  Materials Posted, TCS Chapter 0, TCS Chapter 1     Wed 25 August (3:30-4:45pm)  
Full class meeting: open question time (come by Maury Hall 209 to meet with the instructors and ask any questions you have about the course)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>This syllabus is a &amp;ldquo;living document&amp;rdquo; subject to change as we adapt during the semester. The course website is managed through a public github repository, so you can see past versions there.
The version as posted on the first day of class is here. 
Overview Course Description: The goal of this course is to understand the fundamental limits on what can be efficiently computed in our universe and other possible (or imaginary) universes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2021 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</guid>
      <description>[Updated 18 August 2021]
The cs3102 course will be offered in Fall 2021, co-taught by Nathan&amp;nbsp;Brunelle and David&amp;nbsp;Evans.
Class meetings will be Mondays and Wednesday, 3:30pm - 4:45pm in Maury Hall 209. We will be sending out an email next week with details on the in-person class meetings, but they are being planned in a way that prioritizes safety and comfort while offering an in-person class experience.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be putting more information here about the course as the start of the semester approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources for cs3102. If you discover other resources you think would be helpful for students in the class, please let us know to add them here.
Course Book Main Website
Full Text PDF
Github (if you have corrections or suggestions for the book, submit them to Boaz Barak here; useful contributions will be worth bonus points in the course, so let us know if you have a pull request accepted or start a useful issue)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/python/</guid>
      <description>If you already have python3 on your machine, you should be good to go for the programming problems.
If you don’t, please follow these directions to download Python and PyCharm (you’re welcome to use any IDE that you want, we semi-arbitrarily picked PyCharm).
Windows  Install Python 3.6.4 (If you have a different version of Python, you still must install 3.6.4 seperately!):
 Download the executable x86-64 installer from python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Evals</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/peer_evals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/peer_evals/</guid>
      <description>Purpose Your first peer evaluation is to occur after your week 4 assessed meeting (it is due with your writeup). You will evaluate all cohort-members (including yourself) on 5 items. Each item will have 4 options: exceeds expectations, meets expectations, room for improvement, unsatisfactory. The chart describes example behaviors to merit each category. Select the best fit.
Your responses will be aggregated, anonymized, and then shared with the cohort-mate whom they’re about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to cs3102! The main goals for the first week are:
 Set up the cohorts, and have each group get to know each other and figure out how you will work well together to ensure everyone in your cohort succeeds in the course and has a good experience learning with others.
 Re-awaken the mathematical thinking skills you have (hopefully) developed previously, and start applying them to problems in theory of computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week10/</guid>
      <description>Goals Last week, we used a counting argument to show that there must be some uncomputable functions (&amp;ldquo;some&amp;rdquo; here means infinitely many), but we didin&amp;rsquo;t find a specific uncomputable function. This week, we prove that a particular function is uncomputable, and explore the implications of finding an uncomputable function.
The main goals for Week 10 are to:
 Identify specific functions that cannot be computed by Turing Machines Develop skills for identifying uncomputable problems Build strategies for showing new problems to be uncomputable Undertand the definition of Universality in the context of Turing Machines  Schedule    Day &amp;ldquo;Monday&amp;rdquo; Cohort &amp;ldquo;Tuesday&amp;rdquo; Cohort &amp;ldquo;Wednesday&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;Cohort &amp;ldquo;Thursday&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;Cohort &amp;ldquo;Friday&amp;rdquo; Cohort     Wed 27&amp;nbsp;Oct Preparation (week 9) (week 9) (week 9) (week 9)   Thurs 28&amp;nbsp;Oct Preparation Preparation (week 9) (week 9) (week 9)   Fri 29&amp;nbsp;Oct Preparation Preparation Preparation (week 9) (week 9)   Sat 30&amp;nbsp;Oct Prep Cohort Meeting Preparation Preparation Preparation (week 9)   Sun 31&amp;nbsp;Oct Revision Prep Cohort Meeting Preparation Preparation Preparation   Mon 1&amp;nbsp;Nov Assessed Meeting Revision Prep Cohort Meeting Preparation Preparation   Tues 2&amp;nbsp;Nov Writeup Due Assessed Meeting Revision Prep Cohort Meeting Preparation   Wed 3&amp;nbsp;Nov (week 11) Writeup Due Assessed Meeting Revision Prep Cohort Meeting   Thurs 4&amp;nbsp;Nov (week 11) (week 11) Writeup Due Assessed Meeting Revision   Fri 5&amp;nbsp;Nov (week 11) (week 11) (week 11) Writeup Due Assessed Meeting   Sat 6&amp;nbsp;Nov (week 11) (week 11) (week 11) (week 11) Writeup Due    Cohort Problems These are the problems you should discuss in your Cohort Meeting, and everyone in your cohort should be prepared to present and discuss solutions to at the Assessed Cohort Meeting:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week11/</guid>
      <description>Goals This week, we hope you&amp;rsquo;ll become comfortable proving functions are uncomputable (and occasionally, computable). We introduce the &amp;ldquo;proof by reduction&amp;rdquo; technique, which is a tremendously useful way to prove properties about problems, and (as you will see in the Algorithms class) also to develop and analyze algorithmic solutions.
The main goals for Week 11 are to:
 Become comfortable with the terms decidable, recognizable, and computable, and how we talk about these properties for languages, functions, and problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week12/</guid>
      <description>Goals This week we arrive at the most famous and foundational open problem in Computer Science (and, arguably, in all of Mathematics, and more questionably, perhaps of all human creative endeavor): is it substantially easier to verify the solution to a (certain very broad and common type of) problem, than it is to find that solution? (stated more formally in computer science as &amp;ldquo;P = NP?&amp;rdquo;.
The main goals for Week 12 are to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2: Bit Strings and Computing Models At this point you should have been assigned to a cohort and met with them at least twice (once during your assigned prep time and once during your assessed time with a TA). This week, our main goals are:
 Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve had some cohort experience, reflect on how to make the most out of your cohort experience this semester. Begin exploration of the theory of computing, most importantly seeing the motivations for significant themes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week3/</guid>
      <description>Week 3: Circuits and Sugar The main goals for Week 3 are to:
 Show how simple models of computing can result in complex behavior. Begin building a bridge from theoretical models of computing (like straightline programs and boolean circuits) to practical implementations of computing (like Python and integrated circuits). Explore the powers and limitations of a model of computing, including being able to understand the details of how to use that model, and why it is defined in the way chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week4/</guid>
      <description>Week 4: Universal gates and Evaluation The main goals for Week 4 are to:
 Implement and use the EVAL function. This is our first exposure to a modul of computing which is able to simulate an instance of itself. This idea is fundamental to the practice of computer science, as it enables us to have arbitrarily reprogrammable machines which run with fixed hardware. Begin classifying functions by complexity (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week5/</guid>
      <description>Goals The main goals for Week 5 are to:
 Understand what a complexity class is and how to provide properties about circuit-size complexity classes. Learn the asymptotic operators (Big-O, &amp;Omega;, and &amp;Theta;) and how to use them correctly. Be able to both intuitively understand what functions are in O(f(n)), and to prove membership or non-membership. Be able to connect the formal definitions of computing costs to practical questions about the cost of computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week6/</guid>
      <description>Goals The main goals for Week 6 are to:
 Synthesize what we have learned about finite computation in the first 5 weeks, and start exploring unbounded computation.
 Appreciate the connection between functions and languages, and the different ways of talking about computation.
 Understand and be able to formally define a Finite State Automaton, and to reason about the language accepted (or function computed) by a Deterministic Finite Automaton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week7/</guid>
      <description>Goals The main goals for Week 7 are to:
 Review and synthesize the material you learned in Weeks 1-5.
 Get some practice taking an exam without the stress and logistical challenges of a graded, in class exam.
  Schedule Monday and Tuesday are Fall Reading Days, and Tuesday is Ada Lovelace Day. There is no class meeting on Monday, October 11, and no assessed cohort meetings this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week8/</guid>
      <description>Goals The main goals for Week 8 are to:
 Understand the proof that Regular Expressions are equivalent in power to Deterministic Finite Automata. This is a long proof, split over 4 videos, but is something we hope everyone understands in detail. The methods used in the proof are similar to ones we have seen before in showing equivalence of NAND-Circ and Boolean circuits, but is a fair bit more complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week9/</guid>
      <description>Goals This week, we introduce the most important and widely used model of computation, the Turing machine, and start to address the big question of what can and cannot be computed by any machine with a finite description.
The main goals for Week 9 are to:
 Understand what cannot be computed by a finite automaton and why. Use and understand Turing Machines as a model of computing. Study a definition of computability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>