<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>The syllabus for Fall 2021 will be posted here before the start of the semester. Until then, you can see the Fall 2020 Syllabus to get an idea what the course will be like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2021 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</guid>
      <description>[Updated 18 August 2021]
The cs3102 course will be offered in Fall 2021, co-taught by Nathan Brunelle and David Evans.
Class meetings will be Mondays and Wednesday, 3:30pm - 4:45pm in Maury Hall 209. We will be sending out an email next week with details on the in-person class meetings, but they are being planned in a way that prioritizes safety and comfort while offering an in-person class experience.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be putting more information here about the course as the start of the semester approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources for cs3102. If you discover other resources you think would be helpful for students in the class, please let us know to add them here.
Course Book Main Website
Full Text PDF
Github (if you have corrections or suggestions for the book, submit them to Boaz Barak here; useful contributions will be worth bonus points in the course, so let us know if you have a pull request accepted or start a useful issue)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>The schedule for Fall 2021 will be posted here before the start of the semester. Until then, you can see the Fall 2020 Schedule to get an idea what the course will be like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>