<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory of Computation</title>
    <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Theory of Computation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uvatoc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Pledge</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/pledge/</guid>
      <description>Honor Expectations As a student at the University of Virginia, you are trusted to be honorable and expected to behave in ways that merit that trust. We take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment for everyone. In particular, students in cs3102 are expected to follow these rules throughout the course:
I will not lie, cheat or steal. If I am unsure whether something would be considered lying, cheating or stealing, I will ask before doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Semester</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/starting/</guid>
      <description>First Class Meeting Our first scheduled class is Wednesday, 25 August, 3:30-4:45pm in Maury Hall 209 (weather permitting, we will also use the Ampitheater space outside Maury).
For this optional first class meeting, we will have an open &amp;ldquo;meet and greet&amp;rdquo; with an opportunity to ask any questions you would like of the course instructors, and an opportunity for students who wish to form their own cohorts (details below) to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>For the open help schedule, see Open Student Hours.
For the detailed weekly schedule for each cohort, see one of the week postings (e.g., Week 1).
IntroductionWeek 1: Mathematical Definitions
Wed 25 AugustMaterials Posted, TCS Chapter 0, TCS Chapter 1Wed 25 August (3:30-4:45pm)Full class meeting: open question time (come by Maury Hall 209 to meet with the instructors and ask any questions you have about the course)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Overview Course Description: The goal of this course is to understand the fundamental limits on what can be efficiently computed in our universe and other possible (or imaginary) universes. These limits reveal deep and mysterious properties about information, communication, and computing, as well as practical issues about how to solve problems.
Two fundamental questions about any problem are:
 Can it be solved using a machine of a certain type? (computability) How much does it cost to solve it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2021 Course</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/fall-2021-course/</guid>
      <description>[Updated 18 August 2021]
The cs3102 course will be offered in Fall 2021, co-taught by Nathan Brunelle and David Evans.
Class meetings will be Mondays and Wednesday, 3:30pm - 4:45pm in Maury Hall 209. We will be sending out an email next week with details on the in-person class meetings, but they are being planned in a way that prioritizes safety and comfort while offering an in-person class experience.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be putting more information here about the course as the start of the semester approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources for cs3102. If you discover other resources you think would be helpful for students in the class, please let us know to add them here.
Course Book Main Website
Full Text PDF
Github (if you have corrections or suggestions for the book, submit them to Boaz Barak here; useful contributions will be worth bonus points in the course, so let us know if you have a pull request accepted or start a useful issue)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uvatoc.github.io/week1/</guid>
      <description>Content for Week 1 will be posted soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>